today I'm going to do a quick review of
two cabooses that were just released in
August of 2023 from walther's Mainline
these are international cabooses
two different Road names here Gulf
Mobile in Ohio and Illinois Central Gulf
so I'm going to go ahead and do
one unboxing here I'll just this is the
first one I grabbed the Illinois Central
golf
if you watch my channel quite a bit you
know that
about a year ago tangent really released
some
high-end Illinois Central caboosas that
were complete with lighting effects
high levels of details the walther's
main line is going to be more of your
economy version rail car it's going to
be priced to where you can get a fairly
highly detailed
Caboose for reasonable affordable price
so just depending upon where you're at I
picked these up mostly because
it's not overly common
to be able to get anything Gulf Mobile
in Ohio let alone cabooses I think I've
been doing
doing this pretty serious for about 10
years now and this is the first time
that there's been a new release of what
would be considered
more of a diesel Erica Booth so
part of the reason why I picked these up
so
I talked through the unpackaging pretty
simple just a plastic cradle with an
outer plastic sleeve you did notice some
manufacturers wrapped their model in
like a plastic sheet there was nothing
like that in here it was just set nicely
in that cradle and it was easy to get
out of the package
just gonna do a quick
detail look here at the Illinois Central
and I'll pull the gulf mobile Ohio over
here
um you know again this is a value line
so the details aren't as
precise as what you would get on a on a
higher end scale model
but you still have the end ladders the
chimney
um
turn it around so you can see the end
here
the details are again they're not quite
as precise
you know scale wise the ladders are
pretty thick but you know again they're
pretty durable if you get on some of the
the higher end
they're more scaled size and with that
they're just smaller and they just don't
have a lot of uh
durability to them there can be pretty
fragile
um
but you know all in all the the paint
itself is pretty remarkable I think they
did a great job with the Illinois
Central orange uh
let's get another look here one thing I
do know
and I'll zoom in here in just a second
they do have the holes pre-drilled or at
least pre-molded if you wanted to add
itional handrails and things and I do
know that Walthers makes a caboose
detail kit so you can go out and
purchase that and you can add some
additional grab irons to to these
particular caboosas
here's just a little bit closer look at
it
so this is considered to be a wide
vision Caboose but the the couple is
still flush with the side some of them
do have the extended
a couple of where it hangs over the side
of the the cabooses to give the
conductor just a little bit more
visibility for it for the freight train
but you know again
these would look great
sitting in the yard you know if you need
if you have a scene to where you need
some caboosas in a yard or on a caboose
track uh these will fit the belt pretty
nicely
[Music]
and again here's the gulf Mobile in Ohio
I was really excited about this when I
saw these were coming out
again
the the model itself is identical to the
Illinois Central Gulf in terms of the
details
there's no
Road name specific details or features
that you would find on one versus the
other so this is the exact same model
just a little bit different paint
you can see that they painted the
handrails and the ladders yellow just
for a little bit more of a safety
safety aspect for the conductors I can
just take a look at the other end here
and this one I'll flip it over here and
zoom in
there's some detail underneath but again
not to the level of what you would come
to find on a more higher end there are
some of the brake hoses and and
cylinders and things
but
you know like I said
paint Scheme wise this looks great I can
pick up
the uh you know the the accessory kit to
add some more grab irons and things to
these particular cabooses
here's just a little bit closer view of
the trucks
so I haven't had these on my layout yet
to see how they
run and operate
Weight Wise they have a good amount of
weight to them I unfortunately don't
know exactly where my
scale is to be able to weigh these to
see if they meet nmra standards as far
as weight goes but but they do have
they they feel pretty heavy I'm going to
say that they've got to be really close
to being
pretty close to the manufacturers or the
national model railroad associations
weight minimum for for a caboose or rail
car so
these look good I'm gonna go ahead and
get them up on the layout and see how
they run
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
all right
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
thank you
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Laughter]